Open eye.
睁开眼睛。
AI
AI
plus
plus
mini O mini O
mini O mini O
Open.ch.
Open.ch。
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
小心！ 外国的！ 外国的！
program. We are going to be releasing
程序。 我们将推出
two models 03 and 04
两款车型，分别是 03 型和 04 型
mini. These are the first models where
迷你车。 这是
top scientists tell us they produce
顶尖科学家告诉我们，这些模型能够产生
legitimately good and useful novel
真正优秀且有用的创新
ideas.
想法的首批模型。
We've seen great results in
我们在法律领域取得了显著成果
law. Talking to one of my co-workers
。 昨天我和一位同事聊天时
yesterday, he said that 03 came up with
，他说 03 提出了
a great idea for system architecture.
一个很棒的系统架构想法。
It's like we we haven't really seen
感觉我们以前从未见过这样的景象
this. And the thing that's really
。
amazing about these models is that
这些模型真正令人惊叹之处在于，
they're not just models, they're really
它们不仅仅是模型，它们实际上是
AI systems. We've trained them to use
人工智能系统。 我们已经训练它们使用
tools, which is not something that we
工具，这是我们
had done with our previous reasoning
之前的推理
models. They actually use these tools in
模型所没有做过的事情。 实际上，他们在解决难题的过程中，会在思路中运用这些工具
to solve a hard problem. For example,
。 例如，
we've seen 03 use like 600 tool calls in
我们看到 03 连续使用了大约 600 次工具调用来
a row trying to solve a really hard
尝试解决一个非常困难的
task. And we're going to be making these
任务。 我们将从今天开始逐步推出这些
models incrementally uh available
模型，并
starting today, rolling out as quickly
尽快
as we can in our API and chat GBT.
在我们的 API 和聊天 GBT 中推出。
to to my heart is their ability in
我非常看重的一点是他们的
software engineering and not just
软件工程能力，他们不仅能
producing sort of, you know, one-off
编写一些一次性的
pieces of code, but really working in
代码，还能在
real code bases. I I found that these
实际的代码库中工作。 我发现这些
models are actually better than I am at
模型实际上比我更擅长
navigating through our OpenAI codebase,
浏览我们的 OpenAI 代码库，
which is really useful. Definitely
这真的很有用。 肯定
better than I am. See for me a long time
比我强。 很久以前就见过我了
ago. Yes. Yes. But it just helps you get
。 是的。 是的。 但这确实能帮助你完成
so much more done. And so we're really
更多的工作。 因此，我们非常
excited to bring these to the world and
兴奋地将这些产品带给全世界，并期待
see what you will all do with them.
看到大家会如何使用它们。
All right, we're going to show you some
好的，接下来我们将向大家展示
things that 03 can do. Uh, I'll start
03的一些功能。 嗯，我先举
with a science example. So, this will be
个科学方面的例子。 所以，这将是
a physics poster. So, I'm going to let
一张物理海报。 所以，我
03 start thinking now so it can take its
现在要让 03 开始​​思考，让它有
time. Um, what I'm going to feed it is a
时间慢慢来。 嗯，我要喂给它看的是
that I did in 2015, so 10 years ago. And
我2015年做的一个物理实习项目的海报，也就是10年前的事了。
uh this poster or the project was
这张海报或者说这个项目原本是要
supposed to estimate a quantity called
估算一个叫做
the proton is vector scalar charge. It's
质子的量，它是矢量标量电荷。 它
a beyond the standard model of particle
超越了粒子物理学的标准模型
physics. uh quantity that tells you how
。 呃，这个量可以告诉你
short inter short range interactions uh
短程相互作用有多短，呃，
uh how strong they are. And what you'll
它们的强度有多大。 你会
see is that the model 03 is is zooming
看到03型模型正在放大显示
in. It's kind of like browsing around
。这有点像在这里四处浏览
here. I'll zoom out just so we get a
。 我把镜头拉远一点，这样我们就能
little bit better view. And it is it is
看得更清楚一些。 它似乎在
kind of looking for the right quantities
寻找
for uh for the question I asked it,
我提出的问题所需的正确数量，也
which is to basically find this result
就是找到
that I had and compare it to recent
我得到的结果并将其与最近的
literature. But there's a small twist.
文献进行比较。 但事情还有一点小小的转折。
Uh the result actually isn't in the
呃，结果其实不在
poster, and that's because I didn't have
海报上，那是因为我当时还没有
it yet. Uh so although it's in like the
结果。 呃，虽然它在
final paper for this project, it's not
这个项目的最终论文里，但并没有出现
in this poster and uh I'm actually
在这张海报里，呃，我实际上是
asking 03 to do the rest of the project
请 03 帮我完成这个项目的其余部分
for me essentially. He uses the same
。 他在 OpenAI 也使用了同样的
trick at OpenAI. Yeah. Yeah, it's true.
技巧。 是的。 是的，没错。
It's true. Uh great. So it found the
没错。 哦，太好了。 它找到了
plot that I wanted it to find. Uh it's
我想要的那个地块。 呃，它
supposed to figure out that it needs to
应该能算出需要
like find the slope of this plot,
找到这个图的斜率，
extrapolate down to a specific like
外推到特定的
physical quark mass, and then like grab
物理夸克质量，然后获取
that quantity and then actually apply
该量，再应用
another quantity to normalize that
另一个量来归一化该
value. Um, and I think it is already
值。 嗯，我觉得它已经
kind of figured out that this is what it
大致明白它应
should do, but it is just spending a
该做什么了，但它只是在花
little bit more time exploring the
更多的时间来探索
image. Okay, it's good. It's it's it's
图像。 好的，没问题。 它
now going to browse the web for recent
现在将浏览网络以查找最新
results. Yeah. Why is it searching the
结果。 是的。 它为什么要搜索
web? Uh, well, I think I actually did I
网络？ 呃，好吧，我想我其实
did I ask it? I said, oh yeah, find any
问过这个问题了？ 我说，哦，对，找找
recent findings that have like updated
最近有没有更新的估算数据之类的研究结果
estimates. So now it's like just looking
。 所以现在就像是在查阅
at like the literature and seeing what
文献，看看其他
people have done and how it compares to
人做了什么，以及这些结果与
I eventually arrived at. And how long do
我最终得出的结果有何不同。
you think it would take you to do this
你认为完成这项
task? uh quite a long time. Uh yeah, so
任务需要多长时间？ 嗯，相当长一段时间了。 嗯，是的，
I mean it took me a long time just to
我的意思是，我花了很长时间才
remember uh what my poster even meant in
想起来我的海报
the first place. Uh and it also I also
最初到底是什么意思。 呃，而且，
wasn't wasn't there when I first asked
当我第一次问
it this question. It actually told me
这个问题时，我甚至都没有意识到结果并不存在。 它确实告诉我了这一点，这
that uh which was nice. So many days
挺好的。 我花了好多天时间才重新
just for me to even like onboard myself
投入
back to my my project and then uh a few
到我的项目中，然后可能又花了几天时间才真正开始
search through the literature and I mean
查阅文献，我的意思是，我
it must have just read you know at least
可能
like 10 different papers in a few
在几秒钟内就读完了至少 10 篇不同的论文
seconds for me. So that's that's a huge
。 这样可以
time savings. Uh great. So it has uh
节省大量时间。 哦，太好了。 所以它
summarized my my result here and these
总结了我的结果，这些
numbers look uh correct to me. So it's
数字在我看来是正确的。 所以它的
figured out like there's like this
计算方法是这样的：有一个
unnormalized value that it's like
未归一化的值，它是
estimated by extrapolating and that when
通过外推法估计的；当
you uh multiply by this specific uh
你乘以这个特定的
constant that it will reormalize it and
常数时，它会重新归一化，然后
it says okay you would have ended up uh
它会说，好的，你会得到这个值，这
with this which is somewhat close. I
有点接近。 我
think it ended up around like 1.2 in my
觉得我论文里的最终结果大概是 1.2 左右
my paper. And uh then it compares with
。 然后，它与
the actual literature here. So there's a
这里的实际文献进行了比较。 所以有
few different estimates and uh looks a
几种不同的估算结果，嗯，看起来
little close, I'd say. So let's see what
比较接近，我想。 让我们看看上面
it says. Uh it says my bear value looks
写了什么。 呃，它说我的熊市价值看起来
high because it needs to be reormalized.
很高，因为它需要重新调整。
That's correct. Uh after I you multiply
没错。 嗯，乘以
by that, you get something that's more
那个值之后，你会得到一个
consistent with the state-of-the-art
与目前最先进的
results. That's great. Um but it says my
结果更加一致的结果。 那太棒了。 嗯，但是它说我的
precision isn't isn't as good as the
精度不如最先进的
state-of-the-art, which is fine. Uh you
水平，这也没关系。 呃，你
know, it was an internship. Not bad.
知道，那是一份实习工作。 不错。
Exactly.
确切地。
I'll take it. I'll take it. So it seems
我要买它。 我要买它。 所以这似乎
like it's still a reasonable estimate
仍然是一个合理的估计，只是
that maybe has a little bit more
可能
uncertainty than uh recent results which
比最近的结果稍微有些不确定性，这
is great. So the field has made progress
很好。 所以这个领域已经取得了进展，这真是
uh which is awesome to
太棒了
see.
。
for uh so we wanted to start out by
因此，我们首先想
showing some results on standard
展示
benchmarks for these models in math,
这些模型在数学、
coding and science. So in these plots,
编程和科学领域的标准基准测试中的一些结果。 因此，在这些图中，
the dark yellow bars are the new set of
深黄色条形代表新
models and the light yellow bars are the
模型集，浅黄色条形代表
old set of models. And we see a pretty
旧模型集。 我们看到了相当
substantial boost. So on Amy, which is a
大的增长。 所以在 Amy 这个难度
hard math contest, 04 mini gets 99%
很高的数学竞赛中，04 mini 的准确率达到了 99%，
accuracy with tools pretty much
而且评估工具几乎已经
saturating the eval. On code forces,
饱和。 在代码力量测试中，
these models get over 2700, which place
这些模型得分超过 2700 分，跻身
them in the top 200 contestants in the
世界前 200 名参赛者之列
world. And GPQA is a set of hard PhD
。  GPQA 是一系列难度极高的博士
level questions. and 03 gets over 83%.
级别问题。  03 的得票率超过 83%。
Which is pretty incredible. So beyond uh
这真是太不可思议了。 除了
math science, we also want to share you
数学科学之外，我们还想分享，
know a lot of you I know use these
我知道你们很多人都在使用这些
models for coding and to share some
模型进行编码，并分享一些
practical coding benchmarks. So on sweet
实用的编码基准。 所以，在 Sweet
answer bunch and a poly dot we achieve
Answer Bundle 和 Poly Dot 上，
when it's to use tools and to end
当使用工具并最终
without any harness or any specific uh
无需任何工具或任何特定的
things like this. Uh we also wanted to
类似东西时，我们使用该模型实现了最先进的结果。 我们还想
show some numbers for standard
展示一些标准
multimodal benchmarks and uh these
多模态基准测试的数据，这些
numbers are just crazy on MMU, math
数据在 MMU、Math
vista, charive and v var. Uh so we
Vista、Charive 和 Vvar 上简直令人难以置信。 嗯，我们
really hope these models are useful for
真心希望这些模型对
your multimodal tasks as well. Yeah,
您的多模态任务也有帮助。 是的，
this is really you know applying the
这实际上是将
reasoning paradigm to multimodel which
推理范式应用于多模型，这在
was previously not possible and now as
以前是不可能的，而现在正如
Brandon demoed the model is able to
Brandon 所演示的那样，该模型能够
manipulate the image directly in the
在思维链中直接操纵图像，
chain of thought and that leads to a
这
huge increase in capability for
极大地提高了
multimodel. Yeah. I finally want to
多模型的能力。 是的。 最后，我想
share another few evals that uh we run
分享一些我们在外部运行的评估结果
externally. So humanity tax exam as you
。 所以，正如你
can see our 03 model is able to get
所看到的，我们的 03 模型能够
close to deep research uh but 03 will
接近深度研究，但是 03 的
run much faster and of course much fewer
运行速度要快得多，当然，
rate limits in charge if you are using
如果你在管理中使用它，其费率限制也会少得多
it in charge. Uh so we think it's a very
。 嗯，所以我们认为这是一个非常
cool model if you do not need a full
酷的模型，如果你不需要像
report like what deep research produces
深度研究那样的完整报告，
but instead I still interested in some
但仍然对一些
agentic behavior uh to kind information.
能动行为的信息感兴趣的话。
So in these plots we show the
因此，在这些图中，我们以
performance on the y-axis against the
y 轴表示性能，
estimated inference cost on the x-axis
以 x 轴表示估计的推理成本，
and we see that 04 mini is quite a bit
我们可以看到，
better than 03 mini for any given
对于任何给定的推理成本，04 mini 都比 03 mini 好得多
inference cost. Additionally uh one
。 此外，
thing that is not shown here is that 04
这里没有提到的一点是，04 款
mini is a multimodel model and like 03
mini 是一款多型号车型，就像 03 款
mini. So if you need a small and fast
mini 一样。 所以，如果你需要一个小型、快速的
multimodel reasoning model um yeah I'm
多模型推理模型，嗯，是的，我
very excited for you guys to try out of
非常兴奋地想让你们尝试一下
mini.
mini。
The results for 03 are even more stark.
03 年的结果更加鲜明。
Um you can see that for uh it can get
你可以看到，它能
the same performance with way less
以更低的
inference cost and if you're willing to
推理成本获得相同的性能，如果你愿意
pay the same amount as 01 then you get a
支付与 01 相同的金额，那么你就能获得
much higher score. Um so these are
更高的分数。 嗯，这些
pretty amazing models. Yeah. And this is
模型真是太棒了。 是的。 这就是
why we're going to replace the 01 models
为什么我们要用新款替换旧款01型的原因
with the new ones. Yes. Um one thing we
。 是的。 嗯，有一点
should mention quickly is that due to uh
需要快速提及，那就是由于
of the optimizations we've done to make
我们进行了一些优化，使得该
the model more useful in general. Uh it
模型更具成本效益，并且总体上也更有用。 呃，它
is not as benchmark optimized as the
不像
numbers we shared for the 12 days of
我们分享的圣诞节十二天的数据那样经过基准测试优化
Christmas. So there might be some small
。 所以上下可能会有一些小的
disparities uh up and down. It generally
差异。
has gone up in multimodel for example.
例如，在多模型车型中，它的价格总体上有所上涨。
uh we still hope that we still think
呃，我们仍然希望，我们仍然认为
that this is a much better model because
这是一个更好的模型，因为
it's much more optimized for real world
它针对实际
use cases and you won't have to wait as
应用场景进行了更优化，而且当你寻求答案时，你无需等待那么
long when you're asking for an answer
长时间，
which you know uh is a real thing with
你知道，呃，对于
these reasoning models. People are
这些推理模型来说，这是一个真实存在的问题。 人们缺乏
impatient. I I am impatient.
耐心。 我没耐心。
So these models are a result of a lot of
所以这些模型是大量
rigorous science ingenuity and
严谨的科学创新和精湛
craftsmanship and we put in more than 10
工艺的成果，我们投入的
times the training compute of 01 to
训练计算量是模型 01 的 10 倍以上才
produce 03. Um, and it was a lot of hard
制作出模型 03。嗯，这凝聚了
work by lots and lots of people, but the
很多人的心血，但
end result was really beautiful to see.
最终的结果确实令人欣喜。
As we scaled up compute on the x-axis,
随着我们扩大 x 轴上的计算规模，
the performance on evals like Amy just
像 Amy 这样的评估的性能也
kept going up. Yeah. So, this is really
持续提升。 是的。 所以，这实际上是
us, you know, going and retracing our
我们重新回顾了
steps through the GPT series, right,
GPT 系列的步骤，对吧，也
which was this kind of predictable scing
就是这种可预测的场景
pre-training. And now the goal is really
预训练。 现在我们的目标是真正努力
we're trying to get through this scaling
解决强化
in RL and showing that as we put in more
学习中的规模化问题，并证明随着我们投入更多
RL comput, we're also able to get
强化学习计算，我们也能够获得
commentary gains.
评论方面的提升。
Open CEO.
开放式CEO。
Open eye cordex
睁开眼睛 cordex
cli
cli
Fore cloud
Fore cloud
codeex. X A L
codeex。  X A L
I CEX
I CEX
CLI CEX CLI
CLI CEX CLI
Fore! Fore! Fore!
前！ 小心！ 小心！